William Maxwell Evarts Collection
William Maxwell Evarts Collection
1842-1893
Evarts, William Maxwell, 1818-1901.
15 folders (SC)
American lawyer and statesman.
3194818
Biographical History
William Maxwell Evarts (1818-1901) was an American lawyer and statesman. He served as U.S. Attorney General (1868-1869) under President Johnson, as U.S. Secretary of State (1877-1881) under President Hayes, and as U.S. Senator from New York (1885-1891).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William Maxwell Evarts Collection consists of biographical material, correspondence, photographs and printed material.
Biographical material contains a photocopy of a biographical sketch of Evarts, from an unknown source.
Correspondence is entirely outgoing, and includes letters to President Abraham Lincoln and other political figures of the day.
Photographs contains an engraving of Evarts.
Printed material consists of printed editions of some of Evarts' opinions in three cases in which he was involved. The Parish will case was notable enough to be covered in the New York Times ("The Parish Will Case," May 5, 1862).
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical.
Related Material
See for books relating to Evarts.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; Evarts, William Maxwell, 1818-1901.; United States. -- Congress. -- Senate.; Attorneys general -- United States.; Cabinet officers -- United States.; Lawyers -- United States.; Legislators -- United States.; Statesmen -- United States.; Correspondence.; Cabinet officers.; Lawyers.; Legislators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Unspecified.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - "Evarts, William Maxwell" biographical sketch, photocopied from unknown source (Sc 36)
  - Invitation to dinner given in his honor, 1891; typescript draft and printed booklet (Sc 36)
- Correspondence, outgoing
  - Hunt, William Henry, 1879-1880 (Sc 36)
  - Lincoln, Abraham, 1863 (Sc 36)
  - Metcalf, Porettus Sutton, 1888 (Sc 36)
  - Minturn, Robert Bowne, 1842 (Sc 36)
  - Morgan, Edwin Denison, 1842 (Sc 36)
  - Pierrepont, Edwards, 1860-1868; 1873-1874,; 1877-1878,; 1881,; 1885,; 1889,; 1890; 3 folders (Sc 36)
  - Robinson, E. Randolph, 1886 (Sc 36)
  - Miscellaneous, 1867; 1883-1884,; 1893 (Sc 36)
- Photographs
  - Photograph of Evarts, undated (Sc 36)
- Printed material
  - The Parish Will Case: Mr. Evarts' Argument in Reply, circa 1857 (Sc 36)
  - The Prize Causes: Mr. Evarts' Brief for the United States, circa 1862 (Sc 36)
  - United States vs. William M. Fullerton, et al. / Official Correspondence, 1869 (Sc 36)